Guide to the Glenway Wescott Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1900-88; Series VII; 11.34; (29 boxes)
  - ART PHOTOGRAPHY
    - Lynes, George Platt
      - Lloyd, Faby, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4578)
      - Loring, Eugene, 1937 Oct 25 (Box 417, Folder 4579)
      - Lynes, George Platt [self-portrait], n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4580)
        Letter on verso from GPL to [GW?]
      - Madison, Guy, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4581)
        4 views on contact print strip
      - McClendon, Carlos, 1947 Sep (Box 417, Folder 4582)
      - McClendon, Carlos, and John Goodwin, 1947 Sep (Box 417, Folder 4583)
      - Marie, Romany, hands of (Box 417, Folder 4584)
      - Martinez, José, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4585)
      - Museum of Modern Art exhibit: "Painters and Sculptors as Illustrators", curated by MW (Box 417, Folder 4586)
        3 views
      - Noyes, Eliot, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4587)
      - Oliver, Maria Rosa, ca. 1946 (Box 417, Folder 4588)
      - Pagano, N. Mark, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4589-4595)
        7 views, (2 prints of one view)
      - Ritter Brothers in bandages (Box 417, Folder 4596)
      - Smutney, Tex, and Buddy Stanley, 1941 (Box 417, Folder 4597)
      - Stanley, Buddy, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4598)
      - [Steichen, Edward?], n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4599)
      - Stravinsky, Igor, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4600)
      - Tomlanovitch, George, 1950 Sep 7 (Box 417, Folder 4601)
      - Visbal, Humberto J., 1954 Oct 15 (Box 417, Folder 4602)
        2 views on contact print strip
      - Wescott, Lloyd, ca. 1932 (Box 417, Folder 4603)
      - Weslow, William, with GW and MW at Stone Blossom (Box 417, Folder 4604)
        3 views on contact print strip
      - Wheeler, Fred Monroe, ca. 1935-40
      - Wyman, Steve, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4605)
      - Yeon, John, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4606)
      - Zorina, Vera, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4607)
      - Zoritch, George, 1939 Mar 30 (Box 417, Folder 4608)
      - Unidentified man, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4609)
      - Unidentified man, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4610)
      - Unidentified man, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4611)
      - Unidentified man, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4612)
      - Unidentified man, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4613)
        2 copy prints
      - Unidentified men, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4614)
        Copy negative
      - Travel snapshots, ca. 1930s (Box 417, Folder 4615)
        Includes shot of MW with Gerard Proost
        and Jan van Krimpen
    - Ostier, A.
      - Man with helmet, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4616)
    - Ray, Satyajit
      - Two street scenes, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4617)
        [possibly Calcutta, 1964]
    - Van Vechten, Carl
      - Group of men at Stage Door Canteen, 1943 Feb 17 (Box 417, Folder 4618)
      - Unidentified man, n.d. (Box 417, Folder 4619)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS OF ARTISTS' WORKS
    - Aguilar, Mauricio, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4620)
    - Avery, Milton, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4621)
    - Benn, Ben, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4622)
    - Berman, Eugene, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4623)
    - Bonnard, Pierre, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4624)
    - Butts, Anthony, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4625)
    - Cadmus, Paul, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4626)
    - Calder, Alexander (Box 418, Folder 4627)
    - Cocteau, Jean, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4628)
    - Courbet, Gustave, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4629)
    - Davies, Arthur B., n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4630)
    - Dinesen, Isak, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4631)
    - [Forat?], S., n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4632)
    - French, Jared, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4633)
    - Graves, Morris, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4634)
    - Hartley, Marsden, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4635)
    - Kauffer, Edward McKnight, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4636)
    - Klee, Paul, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4637)
    - MacIver, Loren, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4638)
    - [Malevich, Kazemir?], n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4639)
    - Mesa, Guillermo, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4640)
    - Otero, Alejandro, 1967-68 (Box 418, Folder 4641)
    - Perlin, Bernard, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4642-4643)
    - Picasso, Pablo, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4644)
    - Rembrandt (Box 418, Folder 4645)
    - Soutines, Chaim, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4646)
    - Steig, William, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4647)
    - Tanguy, Yves, n.d. (Box 418, Folder 4648)
    - Tchelitchew, Pavel
      - Contents of GW's blue binder (Box 419, Folder 4649)
      - Contents of GW's pink binder (Box 419, Folder 4650)
      - Contents of GW's white binder (Box 419, Folder 4651)
      - Erotic subjects, n.d. (Box 419, Folder 4652)
      - Portraits, n.d. (Box 419, Folder 4653-4654)
      - General subjects, n.d. (Box 419, Folder 4655)
    - Tobey, Mark, n.d. (Box 419, Folder 4656)
    - Turner, J.M.W., n.d. (Box 419, Folder 4657-4658)
    - Unidentified, 1978, n.d. (Box 419, Folder 4659)
    - Study prints from museums, n.d. (Box 420, Folder 4660)
    - Royal Doulton china plate owned by MW, n.d. (Box 420, Folder 4661)
    - "Gifts to MOMA 1976", n.d. (Box 420, Folder 4662)
      Includes: Bonnard and caricature of
      MW by Ben Shahn
    - "Photos of artworks given to the Museum of Modern Art in 1977", n.d. (Box 420, Folder 4663)
      Includes: Drawings of MW and of GW
      by Cadmus; drawings of MW and of GPL
      by Tchelitchew
    - Notebook with reproduction of Matisse drawing and photo print of sculptural relief (Box 420, Folder 4664)
  - ALBUMS
    - "M.W. - A snapshot album", ca. 1930-70 (Box 421, Folder 4665)
      Contents:
      Anatole Pohorilenko
      Dr. Philemon S. Lansdale
      Burt Jureny
      James Albert King
      Herbert H. Kauffman
      Ivan Ashby
      Emily Harding (Zimmer)
      Katherine Anne Porter
      Philippe de Rothschild with
      Christopher Fry [clipping]
      William Plomer [clipping]
      Baron Andre Pieyre de Mandiargues,
      Stanislao Lepri, Count Sforzino
      Sforza, and Christian William Miller
      Georg A. Von Ihering
      Stephen Wheeler
      Mrs Nelson Stryker (Emmy)
      Jim and Emily Eng with GW
      Madame Gaston Monteux, GW, MW, and
      "Lupo"
      Jacques Guerin
      Jean Bourgoint
      G.W.
      John Yeon
      Helen Parker
      Frances Lamont Robbins with GW and MW
      GW with Mosher child
      Mr. and Mrs. Woolcott Hooker
      Anatole Pohorilenko and James Graves
      Louise Bogan
      Louis and Jetti Ames
    - Black Album #1, ca. 1925-70 (Box 421, Folder 4666)
      Anthony Butts and Mrs. Colville Hyde
      Pauline de Rothschild
      Lloyd Wescott
      GPL
      Gladys Campbell
      Barbara Wescott
      Dorothee Nolan
      Nelson Lansdale
      Anna Felderhof
      R. L. and Fanny M. Cottenet's house
      in Charleston
      Mr. and Mrs. Howard Sachs
      Agnes Rindge
      Grevis Melville
      John Stevenson and Robert Wilson
      with MW and GW
      Celso Biagini
      Anna M. Wheeler
      Richard Wheeler
      Charles Rain and Elizabeth Wescott
      Lloyd Goff
      Joseph Lane
      Philip Harmon
      Jean Boy
      Mark Pagano with GW
      Nelson Doubleday, Ellen Violett,
      Madeleine Violett, young Nelson D.,
      and Ellen Doubleday
      Bobsy Goodspeed Chapman
      Marianne Moore with her family and MW
      Marianne Moore in academic robes
      Mr and Mrs Philip Brewster Heartt and
      son Stephen
      Jesus-Maria Martinez
      Marcel Castaing
      Christian William Miller
      Charles Rain
      George Montgomery
      Cesare Pavani, Christian William
      Miller, Leonore Fini, and Stanislao
      Lepri
      Christian Berard
      Mauricio Aguilar
      le Comte de la Celle with MW
      Elizabeth Wescott and Joseph Ecker
      Louis Ames
      W.H. Auden, E.E. Cummings, Archibald
      MacLeish, Marianne Moore, William
      Carlos Williams, Edith Sitwell, and
      Sir Osbert Sitwell [clipping]
      Pauline and Philippe de Rothschild
      Raymond Mortimer with MW
    - Black Album #2, n.d. (Box 421, Folder 4667)
      Contents: Travel photos and postcards
      from Connecticut and Massachusetts
    - Gray Album #1, ca. 1930s-50s (Box 422, Folder 4668)
      Fritz Brinzer and wife
      Kenneth MacLeish
      Christian Bérard
      Jean-Pierre Brasseur
      Janet Flanner
      Jared French
      Ruth Ford and MW
      David Herbert
      David Leavitt, Hal Wilmeth, Anna and
      Giulio Caparella
      Grace Moore, W. Somerset Maugham,
      Josephine Crane, and GW
      Raymond Mortimer
      Wilbur Pippin
      Elly Ney [clipping]
      Patrick O'Higgins
      Ralph Pomeroy
      Katherine Anne Porter with GPL,
      GW, and MW
      Dick Sisson
      Deborah Wescott Clark
      Lloyd Wescott, Edward James, and Dick
      Sisson
      Jérome Sutter
      Pavel Tchelitchew
      Philip Lamantia, Pavel Tchelitchew
      and Parker Tyler
      Pavel Tchelitchew, Charles Henri Ford,
      and MW
      Emmy Winthrop
      John Yeon, Barbara Wescott, and MW
    - Gray Album #2, ca. 1920s-40s (Box 422, Folder 4669)
      Elie Kanai
      Gore Vidal [clipping]
      Edgar and Margaret Wind
      Rodney Chase and Mrs. Haskell
  - MUSEUM OF MODERN ART
    - Publicity photos, ca, 1940s-50s (Box 423, Folder 4670)
    - Buildings, n.d. (Box 423, Folder 4671)
    - MW visit to New Delhi, India, 1975 (Box 423, Folder 4672)
    - MW visits to Puerto Rico, 1953, 1955 (Box 423, Folder 4673)
    - MW receiving visitors/visiting artists, ca. 1940-80 (Box 423, Folder 4674)
      Includes:
      W. Somerset Maugham
      Irita Van Doren
      Marc Chagall
      Henry Miller
      Harold Holt
      Mrs. Bernard Gimbel
      Patrick F. Lannan
      Richard Lippold
      Dona Maria Carlota de Macedo Soares
      Audrey Hepburn
      Ravi Shankar
    - Marianne Moore at MOMA, 1953, n.d. (Box 423, Folder 4675)
      Includes photo with: Marc Chagall,
      Alexander Calder, and Martha Graham
    - International Council trip to Chile, n.d. (Box 423, Folder 4676)
    - International Council trip to Naples, 1962 Jul 15 (Box 423, Folder 4677)
    - Events
      - "Airways to Peace" exhibit, ca. 1945 (Box 423, Folder 4678)
      - Gene Autry party, 1951 (Box 423, Folder 4679)
      - Bonnard exhibit opening, n.d. (Box 423, Folder 4680)
      - "Cezanne to Miro" exhibit opening in Santago de Chile, 1968 Jun 19 (Box 423, Folder 4681)
      - René d'Harnancourt's birthday party, 1961 May (Box 423, Folder 4682)
      - International Furniture Competition Awards, 1949 Jan 18 (Box 423, Folder 4683)
      - Rene Magritte exhibit opening, ca. 1965 (Box 423, Folder 4684)
      - Marx-Schoenborn Collection exhibit opening, 1965 Nov 1 (Box 423, Folder 4685)
      - "64 Paintings by Matisse" exhibit preview, 1966 Jul 18 (Box 423, Folder 4686)
      - MOMA building opening, 1939 Oct (Box 423, Folder 4687)
      - MOMA 25th anniversary party, 1954 Oct 19 (Box 423, Folder 4688)
      - "Power in the Pacific" exhibit preview, 1945 Jan (Box 423, Folder 4689)
      - [Ben Shahn exhibit?], n.d. (Box 423, Folder 4690)
      - "Textiles and Ornamental Arts of India" exhibit, 1955 (Box 423, Folder 4691)
      - Turner exhibit opening, 1966 Mar 21 (Box 423, Folder 4692)
      - "20th Century Italian Art" exhibit opening, 1949 Jun 28 (Box 423, Folder 4693)
      - Unidentified events, ca. 1930s-60s (Box 423, Folder 4694)
  - VARIOUS SUBJECTS
    - Animals, 1937, n.d. (Box 423a, Folder 4695)
    - Buildings, ca. 1935-70 (Box 423a, Folder 4696)
      Includes: [Stone Blossom?],
      Hay Meadows, Egremont Inn, and
      Lynes' family home in North Egremont,
      Massachusetts
    - Exhibition of Harrison of Paris publications, n.d. (Box 423a, Folder 4697)
    - Interiors, n.d. (Box 423a, Folder 4698)
    - Landscapes and vistas, 1978, n.d. (Box 423a, Folder 4699)
    - Manuscripts by GW, n.d. (Box 423a, Folder 4700)
    - Nudes, ca. 1935-70 (Box 423a, Folder 4701)
    - Ships, n.d. (Box 423a, Folder 4702)
- Graphic Items, ca. 1915-80; Series VIII; 0.84; (2 boxes)
  Series VIII, Graphic Items, is
  arranged alphabetically.
  - Art cards, blank, n.d. (Box 424, Folder 4703)
  - Artwork originals
    - Clark, Deborah Wescott, drawings, n.d. (Box 424, Folder 4704)
    - de Segonzac, Andre Denoyer, etching-nude woman (Box 424, Folder 4705)
    - [Dufy, Raoul?], etching: "Chapitre VII, Garcon", n.d.
    - Forbes, Donald, portrait of MW, oil on canvas, ca. 1937
    - Harris, William, portrait of MW, pencil and pastel, 1952 (Box 424, Folder 4705a)
    - Harris, William, portrait of MW, silverpoint, 1952
    - Littlefield, William H., portrait of MW, charcoal and pencil, 1936 Oct 16
    - Littlefield, William H., portrait of MW, oil on canvas, 1936 Oct 16
    - Frasconi, [Antonio], "The Cat Reformed by Matrimony," ink and wash
    - Matisse, lithograph: head of a girl, 1951 (Box 424, Folder 4706)
    - Miksche, Michael, drawing: Charles Howard, 1952 Feb 29 (Box 424, Folder 4707)
    - Nozaki, S., silkscreen: "Slopes", n.d. (Box 424, Folder 4708)
    - Pagano, N. Mark, drawings: twig and plant (Box 424, Folder 4709)
    - Perlin, Bernard, portraits of GW (3) and MW (2), silverpoint, 1945-48
    - Perlin, Bernard, portrait of GW, wax pencil, 1965
    - Pozo, Ramiro Jimenez, print: "El Aguador", n.d. (Box 424, Folder 4710)
    - Sullivan, Thomas, sketch: Carl Malouf, 1950 Mar (Box 424, Folder 4711)
    - Tchelitchew, Pavel, portrait of MW, ink and wash, 1935
    - Wescott, Glenway, watercolor: abstract, [1923?] (Box 424, Folder 4712)
    - Unidentified prints (Box 424, Folder 4713)
    - Unidentified, sketches: Monroe Wheeler (Box 424, Folder 4714)
  - Images of People, ca. 1915-80 (Box 424, Folder 4715)
  - Postcards
    - Chateau Mouton Rothschild, n.d. (Box 424, Folder 4716)
    - "Germany and Austria", ca. 1930s (Box 424, Folder 4717)
    - "Germany and Austria Summer 1931" (Box 424, Folder 4718-4719)
    - "Historical and Literary Portraits", ca. 1930s (Box 424, Folder 4720)
    - Living Room at Rosemont, NJ, n.d. (Box 424, Folder 4721)
    - "Luncheon at Hay Meadow," painting by Harold Bruder, n.d. (Box 424, Folder 4722)
    - "Midi", ca. 1930s (Box 424, Folder 4723)
    - "Paintings", ca. 1930s (Box 424, Folder 4724)
    - "Rome and Italy", ca. 1930s (Box 425, Folder 4725)
    - "Sculpture", ca. 1930s (Box 425, Folder 4726)
    - "Ted Szarkowski" by Jared French, n.d. (Box 425, Folder 4727)
    - Villefranche, n.d. (Box 425, Folder 4728)
    - Blank: general subjects, 1930s-80s (Box 425, Folder 4729-4730)
  - Reproductions of Artwork
    - General, 1950s-80s (Box 425, Folder 4731-4732)
    - Picasso, Pablo, ca. 1920s-40s (Box 425, Folder 4733)
    - Tchelitchew, Pavel, ca. 1920s-50s (Box 425, Folder 4734)
    - Reproductions used by GW in lectures, ca. 1940s-50s (Box 425, Folder 4735)
      Includes letter from GW to Art Institute of Chicago, 1956 May 15
- Clippings, 1931-90; Series IX; 10.08; (24 boxes)
  Series IX, Clippings, is arranged
  - Animals and Nature (Box 426, Folder 4736)
  - Architecture and Design, 1946-87 (Box 426, Folder 4737-4741)
  - Art-collectors and socialites, 1954-74 (Box 426, Folder 4742)
  - Art: general, 1936-90 (Box 426, Folder 4743-4747)
  - Art: general, 1936-90 (Box 427, Folder 4748-4756)
  - Art: general, 1936-90 (Box 428, Folder 4757-4766)
  - Art: general, 1936-90 (Box 429, Folder 4767-4776)
  - Art: general, 1936-90 (Box 430, Folder 4777-4787)
  - Art: general, 1936-90 (Box 431, Folder 4788-4790)
  - Art: images, 1931-82 (Box 431, Folder 4791-4795)
  - Athletes, 1972-73 (Box 431, Folder 4796)
  - Book reviews, 1938-87 (Box 431, Folder 4797-4799)
  - Book reviews, 1938-87 (Box 432, Folder 4800-4809)
  - Book reviews, 1938-87 (Box 433, Folder 4810-4818)
  - Book reviews, 1938-87 (Box 434, Folder 4819-4827)
  - Book reviews, 1938-87 (Box 435, Folder 4828-4838)
  - Book reviews, 1938-87 (Box 436, Folder 4839-4849)
  - Book reviews, 1938-87 (Box 437, Folder 4850-4853)
  - Book reviews by Raymond Mortimer, 1940-68 (Box 437, Folder 4854-4855)
  - Book reviews by Raymond Mortimer, 1940-68 (Box 438, Folder 4856)
  - Censorship, 1969-74 (Box 438, Folder 4857)
  - Civil liberties, 1978 (Box 438, Folder 4858)
  - Clippings for Amaya, Mortimer, and Pomeroy, 1960-61, n.d. (Box 438, Folder 4859)
  - "Clippings for MW", 1942-79 (Box 438, Folder 4860-4863)
  - "Criticism" notebook, ca. 1950s
  - Current events, 1934-90 (Box 438, Folder 4864-4866)
  - Current events, 1934-90 (Box 439, Folder 4867-4877)
  - Current events, 1934-90 (Box 440, Folder 4878-4880)
  - Dance, 1952-87 (Box 440, Folder 4881-4886)
  - Fashion, 1933-70, n.d. (Box 440, Folder 4887)
  - Film, 1970-79 (Box 440, Folder 4888-4889)
  - Essays and Articles, 1953-86 (Box 441, Folder 4890-4900)
  - Essays and Articles, 1953-86 (Box 442, Folder 4901-4912)
  - Essays and Articles, 1953-86 (Box 443, Folder 4913-4924)
  - Food and Recipes, 1969-84 (Box 444, Folder 4925-4926)
  - Gardening, 1967-73, n.d. (Box 444, Folder 4927)
  - Homosexuality, 1949-81 (Box 444, Folder 4928-4930)
  - "Literary Clippings" scrapbook, 1962-66 (Box 444, Folder 4931)
  - Literature, 1941-81 (Box 444, Folder 4932-4935)
  - Music, 1941-84 (Box 445, Folder 4936-4942)
  - People
    - "A", 1953-83 (Box 445, Folder 4943)
    - "B", 1958-86 (Box 445, Folder 4944)
    - "C", 1956-76 (Box 445, Folder 4945)
    - "C", 1955-80 (Box 446, Folder 4946-4947)
    - "D", 1952-74 (Box 446, Folder 4948)
    - "E", 1933-71 (Box 446, Folder 4949)
    - "F", 1964-77 (Box 446, Folder 4950)
    - "G", 1968-74 (Box 446, Folder 4951)
    - "H", 1959-84 (Box 446, Folder 4952)
    - "I", 1963-70 (Box 446, Folder 4953)
    - "J-K", 1953-84 (Box 446, Folder 4954-4955)
    - "L", 1964-73 (Box 446, Folder 4956)
    - Lynes, George Platt, n.d. (Box 446, Folder 4957)
    - Maugham, W. Somerset, 1953-75 (Box 446, Folder 4958)
    - Moore, Marianne, 1957-86 (Box 446, Folder 4959)
    - "M", 1938-84 (Box 447, Folder 4960-4961)
    - "N", 1922-79 (Box 447, Folder 4962)
    - "O", 1966-78 (Box 447, Folder 4963)
    - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1951-80 (Box 447, Folder 4964-4965)
    - "P", 1951-85 (Box 447, Folder 4966)
    - "R", 1951-79 (Box 447, Folder 4967)
    - Rothschild, Phillipe and Pauline, 1962-75 (Box 447, Folder 4968)
    - "S", 1948-84 (Box 447, Folder 4969-4971)
    - "T", 1949-78 (Box 447, Folder 4972)
    - "U", 1969-78 (Box 447, Folder 4973)
    - "V", 1964-65 (Box 447, Folder 4974)
    - "W", 1957-83 (Box 448, Folder 4975-4976)
    - "Y", 1952-68 (Box 448, Folder 4977)
    - Unidentified, 1955-78 (Box 448, Folder 4978)
    - Groups, 1950-73 (Box 448, Folder 4979)
    - Multiple people, 1973-82 (Box 448, Folder 4980-4981)
  - Pornography, 1977-81 (Box 448, Folder 4982)
  - Quotations, n.d. (Box 448, Folder 4983-4984)
  - "Reading Matter", 1953-79 (Box 448, Folder 4985-4986)
  - Stamps, 1973-80, n.d. (Box 449, Folder 4987)
  - Theater, 1962-84 (Box 449, Folder 4988-4989)
  - Wescott, Barbara, 1935-77, n.d. (Box 449, Folder 4990)
  - Wescott, Glenway
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1950-76 (Box 449, Folder 4991)
    - Appearance and events, 1949-86, n.d. (Box 449, Folder 4992)
    - Casual mentions, 1947-81, n.d. (Box 449, Folder 4993)
    - Interviews, profiles, 1975-83 (Box 449, Folder 4994-4995)
    - Obituary, 1987 Feb (Box 449, Folder 4996)
    - Quotations, 1943-73 (Box 449, Folder 4997)
  - Wescott, Lloyd, ca. 1957-85, n.d. (Box 449, Folder 4998)
  - Wescott Family, ca. 1975-76 (Box 449, Folder 4999)
  - Wheeler, Monroe, ca. 1943-83 (Box 449, Folder 5000)
  - Wisconsin, n.d (Box 449, Folder 5001)
  - Various subjects annotated by GW, 1952-73, n.d. (Box 449, Folder 5002)
- American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1947-87; Series X; 2.94; (7 boxes)
  Series X, American Academy of Arts and Letters is arranged alphabetically.
  - Agenda for council meeting (Box 450, Folder 5003)
  - Ballots, 1978-81, n.d. (Box 450, Folder 5004)
  - Correspondence
    - American Academy to and from GW, 1947-86, n.d. (Box 450, Folder 5005)
    - General: A-B, 1959-72 (Box 450, Folder 5006)
      Includes: correspondence from
      Jamiluddin Aali; Elizabeth
      Ames; Newton Arvin; Jacques
      Barzun; C.L. Bowra; Van Wyck
      Brooks
    - General: C, 1958-70 (Box 450, Folder 5007)
      Malcolm Cowley; Alexander Calder
    - General: D-F, 1959-76 (Box 450, Folder 5008)
      Willem de Kooning; Marcel
      Duchamp; Janet Flanner; Robert Frost
    - General: G-K, 1959-70 (Box 450, Folder 5009)
      Anthony Hecht; John Hersey
      Aldous Huxley; Randall Jarrell
    - General: L-O, 1960-80 (Box 450, Folder 5010)
      William Maxwell; John O'Hara
      Alexis St. Leger Leger; Harry Levin
      Joan Miro; Vladimir Nabokov
    - General: P-S, 1959-75 (Box 450, Folder 5011)
      Richard Rosenthal; Raphael Soyer
    - General: T-W, 1960-81 (Box 450, Folder 5012)
      Helen Tate; Mark Van Doren; Gore
      Vidal; Richard Wilbur
    - General: Unidentified, 1959-75 (Box 450, Folder 5013)
    - American Academy to MW, 1962 (Box 450, Folder 5014)
  - Leon Edel article: "Government and the Arts" (Box 450, Folder 5015)
  - Election certificate, 1947
  - GW files
    - "The Imalgamation Imbroglio", 1976 (Box 450, Folder 5016)
    - "Censorship", 1959-60 (Box 450, Folder 5017)
    - re. Copyright, 1963 (Box 450, Folder 5018)
    - "Matters of My Profession", 1959-75 (Box 450, Folder 5019)
    - "1959" (Box 451, Folder 5020)
    - "1961" (Box 451, Folder 5021-5023)
  - Letters to Members, 1949-87, n.d. (Box 451, Folder 5024-5026)
  - Letter electing GW to American Academy, 1964 Nov 30 (Box 451, Folder 5027)
  - Listing re. American Academy from "Museums in New York", 1967 (Box 451, Folder 5028)
  - Lists of committee members, n.d. (Box 451, Folder 5029)
  - "LK comments on Academy-Institute History Article by Hellman", n.d. (Box 451, Folder 5030)
  - Manuscripts by GW
    - [Address to MacDowell Colony?], draft fragment, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 451, Folder 5031)
    - Citation: Cyril Connolly, drafts, holograph and typescript, with corespondence, 1974 (Box 451, Folder 5032)
    - Citation to Hannah Josephson, draft typescript carbon, ca. 1965 (Box 451, Folder 5033)
    - Citation to Marcel Joubandeau, drafts, holograph, and typescript carbon, ca. 1965 (Box 451, Folder 5034)
    - Discussion of archives w/ Leon Edel, transcript, annotated, 1970 (Box 451, Folder 5035)
    - Eulogy for William Rose Benet, notes, n.d. (Box 451, Folder 5036)
    - Eulogy for Padraic Colum, notebook, n.d. (Box 452, Folder 5037)
    - Eulogy for Padraic Colum, drafts, holograph and photocopy, ca. 1971-72 (Box 452, Folder 5038)
    - Eulogy for Douglas Moore, drafts, holograph, and typescript (Box 452, Folder 5039)
    - Eulogy for John O'Hara, notebook, ca. 1961-70 (Box 452, Folder 5040)
    - Eulogy for John O'Hara, drafts typescript and photocopy, annotated, 1971 (Box 452, Folder 5041)
    - Forward to catalog of Van Wyck Brooks' papers, drafts with notes, holograph, and typescript, corrected, ca. 1964 (Box 452, Folder 5042)
    - Introduction to reading by Robert Frost, draft, typescript copy, and carbon, ca. 1965 (Box 452, Folder 5043)
    - Introduction for John Hall Wheelock, draft, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 452, Folder 5044)
    - Letter on arts censorship, drafts, typescript, carbon, 1949 (Box 452, Folder 5045)
      Includes: letter from Robert
      E. Sherwood
    - Notes on "History and Organization" (Box 452, Folder 5046)
    - Presentation of award to Alfred Barr, Jr., drafts, holograph, typescript, carbon, and photocopy, corrected, 1968 (Box 452, Folder 5047)
    - Presentation to Felicia Geffen, drafts, holograph, typescript, and carbon, corrected, 1973 (Box 452, Folder 5048)
      Includes copy of citation to FG
      and copy of response from FG
    - Presentation of Award of Distinguished Service to the Arts to Lincoln Kirstein, drafts, typescript copy carbon with notecards (Box 452, Folder 5049)
    - Presentation to Marianne Moore of the Gold Medal for Poetry, drafts, typescript copy, and carbon, 1953 (Box 452, Folder 5050)